<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
         http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
 <responseDate>2021-12-16T13:49:32Z</responseDate>
 <request verb="GetRecord" metadataPrefix="oai_dc" identifier="oai:hrcak.srce.hr:1">https://hrcak.srce.hr/oai/</request>
  <GetRecord>
  <record>
  <header>
   <identifier>oai:hrcak.srce.hr:1</identifier>
   <datestamp>2008-06-03</datestamp>
   <setSpec>journal:1</setSpec>
   </header>
   <metadata>
     <oai_dc:dc
       xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
       xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/
       http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="eng">FOREWORD</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Ante Graovac</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Biserka Pokric</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Drazen Vikic-Topic</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Croatian Chemical Society</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
      <dc:type>text</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://hrcak.srce.hr/1</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier xml:lang="eng">https://hrcak.srce.hr/file/1</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source>Croatica Chemica Acta</dc:source>
      <dc:source>ISSN 0011-1643 (Print)</dc:source>
      <dc:source>ISSN 1334-417X (Online)</dc:source>
      <dc:source>Volume 78</dc:source>
      <dc:source>Issue 2</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights>info:eu-repo/semantics/openAccess</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>Croatica Chemica Acta is at the highest possible level of Open Access, meaning that all content is immediately and freely available to anyone, anywhere, to be downloaded, printed, distributed, read, reused, self archived, and re-mixed (including commercially) without restriction, as long as the author and the original source are properly at-tributed according to the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (CC BY). The author(s) hold the copyright and retain publishing rights without restrictions.
CC BY (Creative Commons Attribution) is the most accommodating of public copyright licenses as defined by Creative Commons, a nonprofit organization that provides legal tools for sharing and use of creative works and research. The CC BY license is recommended for maximum dissemination and use of licensed materials. All content published in Croatica Chemica Acta is available under CC BY, meaning anyone is free to use and reuse the content provided the original source and authors are credited. The copyright is held and retained. The author(s) hold the copyright without restrictions.
CC BY is the appropriate license for publicly funded research; it maximizes the potential for both economic and scholarly impact, protects the rights of authors and strengthens the long-standing tradition of appropriate attribution and credit for scholarship.</dc:rights>
     </oai_dc:dc>
   </metadata>
  </record>
 </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>